<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Learn. Create. Ship.</title>
    <link>https://daryll.codes/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Learn. Create. Ship.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 18:57:03 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daryll.codes/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing,Day 10: On Intermittent Fasting</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-10-on-intermittent-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 18:57:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-10-on-intermittent-fasting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been intermittent fasting over the last month or so, and the results have been dramatic: I&amp;rsquo;ve lost 10 pounds in the last 6 weeks.
Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not a doctor, so try this at your own risk!
This is done without losing fitness as I can somehow bike faster, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some core exercises: I actually feel stronger, despite the weight loss!
My intermittent fasting schedule varies from day to day, but I try to keep my eating window within 6-8 hours: during most days, I start breaking my fast at 2-2:30pm, and eat my last meal at around 8-8:30 pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, Day 9: You Can Make Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-9-you-can-make-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:26:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-9-you-can-make-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to write this blog post on time, as I slept before pushing this article out. I could rationalize and say that I was too tired, but I had an entire day (and to be quite honest, I only really need less than an hour) to do this, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t.
And that&amp;rsquo;s okay. You can&amp;rsquo;t expect every day to go the way you want to. What&amp;rsquo;s important is you pick yourself back up and try again the next day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing: Day 8, An Inhuman Climb</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-8-an-inhuman-climb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 23:15:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-8-an-inhuman-climb/</guid>
      <description>Today, I rode a climb up Tagaytay, Sungay In the Philippines. It&amp;rsquo;s an inhuman climb, with gradients at 15% in the straighter sections and up to 25% in the corners. It&amp;rsquo;s a climb that is difficult to walk on, never mind riding a bike though.
It&amp;rsquo;s often at the edge of our ability that every thing we put in matters. While I&amp;rsquo;ve been religiously training on the bike for the past few months, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a road bike for two years, the Sungay climb&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous gradients exposed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, Day 7: Just Have a One Percent Day</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-7-just-have-a-one-percent-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 22:17:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-7-just-have-a-one-percent-day/</guid>
      <description>There are days where I can say that I&amp;rsquo;m really not that motivated that much. It could be something with my brain or with my sleep or with my food or with my exercise, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone reading this blog to have this illusion that I don&amp;rsquo;t have bad days. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of shitty days.
When those days come along, I ask myself, what is the smallest unit of work that I can do to move me closer to my dreams?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, Day 6: Don&#39;t Do Things You Know You&#39;ll Regret</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-6-dont-do-things-that-youll-regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:54:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-6-dont-do-things-that-youll-regret/</guid>
      <description>You choose the suffering you want to experience. &amp;ldquo;Suffer the pain of discipline or suffer the pain of regret.&amp;rdquo;
As I struggle (and groan at the words that I&amp;rsquo;m typing) to think and push through with this article, I know that at any time, I can just switch to a new tab and continue mindlessly browsing Twitter and Hacker News.
The problem with doing that is that I know that I&amp;rsquo;ll hate myself in the morning when the feeling of having skipped a day clouds over me, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather just kludge through writing this post even if I&amp;rsquo;m really sleepy and tired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, Day 5: Systems Instead of Discipline.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-5-systems-instead-of-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 01:45:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-5-systems-instead-of-discipline/</guid>
      <description>This title is very apt since I&amp;rsquo;m really tired right now (the bike just killed me), but here goes.
You brain has a limited amount of willpower and decisions it can do per day. Don&amp;rsquo;t waste this on stupid shit by creating systems that will incentivize good habits while disallowing bad ones.
Food system: there&amp;rsquo;s no way for my brother and I to eat bad food in the house because we only buy nutritious food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, Day 4: Putting in Reps.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-4-putting-in-reps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 01:11:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-4-putting-in-reps/</guid>
      <description>A huge life goal of mine is to create a body of work that I can ultimately look back on and be proud of. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to build some software that helps a lot of people, or write a blog post that gets someone to take control of their life, or possibly speak at a conference and inspire someone to build their own empire.
If that is to be a reality, then I&amp;rsquo;ll have to put in a certain number of repetitive deliberate practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, Day 3: Always try to do things faster.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-3-always-try-to-do-things-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:44:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-3-always-try-to-do-things-faster/</guid>
      <description>Always ask yourself: is there an easier, faster, and better way of doing things?
If there is, then follow up by asking, would the time spent learning that way save time in the long-term?
I first came into contact with the text editor I use for writing my programs (Vim) 4 years ago, and while it was a nightmare to learn I knew that if I just buckled down and forced myself to learn it for the next 20-100 hours, it would pay off at some point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing, day 2: Base your self-worth on learning.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-2-base-your-self-worth-on-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:24:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-2-base-your-self-worth-on-learning/</guid>
      <description>In my junior and senior years in college, I had absolutely nothing going for me (horrible grades, very few friends, and no money) that I based my self-worth off my greatest &amp;ldquo;strength&amp;rdquo; at the time, which was video games and Magic: The Gathering.
A really low point was when I was trying to construct a resume to look for a call center job after I had been expelled from my college—asides from the schools I attended, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:08:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s something seriously wrong with how I interpret myself as an aspiring writer. For someone who has the audacity to call himself that, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been doing a lot of writing.
My long-standing alibi has been &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll write the horribleness out of my system by just writing a lot of articles&amp;rdquo;, but I seem to always conveniently forget what &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo; means, especially when it comes to hitting &amp;ldquo;commit&amp;rdquo; on my computer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>