<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learn. Create. Ship.</title>
    <link>http://daryll.codes/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learn. Create. Ship.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 18:53:56 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://daryll.codes/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Preparations 😱</title>
      <link>http://daryll.codes/posts/hiking-preparations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 18:53:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daryll.codes/posts/hiking-preparations/</guid>
      <description>1 week before: Preclimb  Confirm itinerary.
 When to leave/meeting place, expected costs, options. Get contact details/person to contact in case of emergency for all hikers. Get a contact person in Manila or wherever you are where you can send climb updates to. Required clothing/tools (cold wear, gloves, trekking poles).  Get hike details.
 How long is the hike/how many days? Do we expect rain or a hot climb?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Guide: Korea in Winter</title>
      <link>http://daryll.codes/posts/travel-guide-korea-in-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 13:18:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daryll.codes/posts/travel-guide-korea-in-winter/</guid>
      <description>Getting the Visa (Philippines): Visa requirements are on the Korean embassy page.
If your parents are retired (don&amp;rsquo;t have an ITR), you can use your ITR as a substitute. My brother is in school so I used my ITR since I was sponsoring his trip.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think you need to be physically present when applying for the Visa. We forgot a requirement (my brother&amp;rsquo;s school certificate) the first time we got there so we re-applied a few days after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start</title>
      <link>http://daryll.codes/posts/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 15:38:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://daryll.codes/posts/start/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start blogging again. And this time I want to stick to this for good (like for the rest of my life). A few years back I did the Project 365 thing where you took a picture of the day for 365 days. I really liked that year since I actively tried to do something per day so surely writing about things should have that kind of effect 😱</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>