<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learn. Create. Ship.</title>
    <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learn. Create. Ship.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:44:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daryll.codes/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: Always try to do things faster.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-3-always-try-to-do-things-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:44:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-3-always-try-to-do-things-faster/</guid>
      <description>Always ask yourself: is there an easier, faster, and better way of doing things?
If there is, then follow up by asking, would the time spent learning that way save time in the long-term?
I first came into contact with the text editor I use for writing my programs (Vim) 4 years ago, and while it was a nightmare to learn I knew that if I just buckled down and forced myself to learn it for the next 20-100 hours, it would pay off at some point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Base your self-worth on learning.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-2-base-your-self-worth-on-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:24:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing-day-2-base-your-self-worth-on-learning/</guid>
      <description>In my junior and senior years in college, I had absolutely nothing going for me (horrible grades, very few friends, and no money) that I based my self-worth off my greatest &amp;ldquo;strength&amp;rdquo; at the time, which was video games and Magic: The Gathering.
A really low point was when I was trying to construct a resume to look for a call center job after I had been expelled from my college—asides from the schools I attended, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap, 1532: Deploying Writing Prompts app, Start</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1532/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 11:46:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1532/</guid>
      <description>On the 1532nd week of my life, I:
 Read: The E-Myth Revisited: Why Most Small Businesses Don&amp;rsquo;t Work and What to Do About It, by Michael E. Gerber Read: Purple Cow: Transform Your Business by Being Remarkable, by Seth Godin. Read: Jab, Jab, Jab, Right Hook: How to Tell Your Story in a Noisy Social World, by Gary Vaynerchuk. Read: The Well-Grounded Rubyist, by David A. Black. Read: Full Stack React, by fullstackreact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Days of Writing</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:08:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/30-days-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s something seriously wrong with how I interpret myself as an aspiring writer. For someone who has the audacity to call himself that, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been doing a lot of writing.
My long-standing alibi has been &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll write the horribleness out of my system by just writing a lot of articles&amp;rdquo;, but I seem to always conveniently forget what &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo; means, especially when it comes to hitting &amp;ldquo;commit&amp;rdquo; on my computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap, 1531: Deploying Transcripto, Women Who Code: Her 2.0, First Century Ride in 2018.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1531/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 23:07:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1531/</guid>
      <description>On the 1531st week of my life, I:
 Read: Domain-Driven Design, by Eric J. Evans. Nearly finished, I hope! Read: Little Bets: How Breakthrough Ideas Emerge from Small Discoveries, by Peter Sims. Read: Linchpin: Are You Indispensable?, by Seth Godin. Read: So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love Read: Eloquent Ruby, by Russ Olsen. Reading: The E-Myth Revisited: Why Most Small Businesses Don&amp;rsquo;t Work and What to Do About It, by Michael E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap, 1530, Speaking at Rubyconf, Walking from Cubao to BGC.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1530/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 16:44:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1530/</guid>
      <description>On the 1530th week of my life, I:
 Die Empty: Unleash Your Best Work Everyday, by Todd Henry. The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business, By Charles Duhigg. Reading: Domain-Driven Design by Eric J. Evans. Nearly finished, I hope! Reading: Full Stack React. Watching: A Cloud Guru AWS Software Architect Online Course. Writing: A blog post on how I use the Pomodoro technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Habits: Pomodoro Technique</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/good-habits-pomodoro-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 20:05:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/good-habits-pomodoro-technique/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone. Let me share a productivity tip that I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for years. It&amp;rsquo;s called the Pomodoro technique. The one sentence summary is that you work in blocks of 25 minutes at a time, resting for five minutes in between. After every four Pomodoros, you can take a longer break (typically 15-20 minutes).
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this technique since I started actually programming professionally. It&amp;rsquo;s really helped me over the last 5 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap, 1529/5000, where I get back to ReactJS and vlog for my job application.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1529/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:45:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1529/</guid>
      <description>On the 1529th week of my life, I:
 Read: Your Brain at Work by David Rock. Reading: Domain-Driven Design by Eric J. Evans. Reading: Die Empty by Todd Henry. Reading: Full Stack React. Watching: A Cloud Guru AWS Software Architect Online Course. Wrote: A blog post on how to focus as a software developer. Biked: 211km.   Coding:  Added Doorkeeper/JWT/controller layer to Daryllxd. Added another view to Daryllxd re: summarizing activity tags for the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Habits: Blocking Out Social Media/Distractions</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/good-habits-blocking-out-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 23:56:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/good-habits-blocking-out-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Folks, this is about blocking out social media during the work day. You&amp;rsquo;re free to use social media for whatever purposes you want in your free time! But if you&amp;rsquo;re like me, who gets easily distracted, and sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t do good work because of all the self-inflicted interruptions, I might have something for you.
For the past six or so weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been hitting 50+ productive hours a week. I&amp;rsquo;ve coded a ton, learned a new programming language, read 5++ books, published 5++ blog posts, biked 20++ times and more than 1000 kilometers, and created my speech for an upcoming work conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap 1528/5000, Domain-Driven Design, Intermittent Fasting, and Sparkfest.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1528/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:56:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1528/</guid>
      <description>Read: Objects on Rails by Avdi Grimm. Reading: Domain-Driven Design by Eric J. Evans. Reading: Your Brain at Work by David Rock. Wrote: A post on all the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Writing: A post on how to focus as a software developer. Biked: 200km. YES. Coding:  Finished reading Objects on Rails, a book I purchased several years ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t understand at the time. I understood everything this time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap 1527/5000, where I learn a new programming language for the first time in four years.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1527/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 08:40:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1527/</guid>
      <description>On the 1527th week of my life, I:
 Read: Crushing It, by Gary Vaynerchuk. Read: The Obstacle Is the Way, by Ryan Holiday. Reading: Programming Elixir, by Jose Valim. Reading: Programming Phoenix, by Chris McCord. Reading: Your Brain at Work, by David Rock. Wrote: Just drafts of articles. I should have! Biked: 186km. Coding:  Habits One, Elixir project. I have authentication and authorization working now, as well as the basic CRUD functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 05:10:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/tools/</guid>
      <description>Like a craftsman has a set of their favorite tools, here are mine:
Software  Text editor: Vim. I practically live in this. Fun fact: I was probably the only Rails programmer who coded in Netbeans on Windows. Shell: zsh. Version control: Git. Searcher: The Silver Searcher. Screen capturing: Kapture.io. OS X navigator: Alfred. File synchronization: Dropbox. Time tracker: Daryllxd. Todo list manager: Todoist but I&amp;rsquo;m starting to hate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap 1526/5000, reviewing my first few journal entries and laughing about it.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1526/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 22:15:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1526/</guid>
      <description>Read: The Art of Manliness articles on focusing. Reading: Incognito: The Secret Lives of the Brain, by David Eagleman. Reading: Smalltalk Best Practice Patterns. Wrote: Blog entry on decluttering. Writing: My speech for Rubyconf! :) Biked: 155km. Coding. Forever project: Daryllxd.  I added a started_at and ended_at to the table. This is huge. The goal of the eternal side project is to keep me productive, and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I can get carried away doing frivolous things from time to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap 1525/5000, the first in what will hopefully be a lifetime of weekly updates.</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1525/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:48:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-1525/</guid>
      <description>Read: Principles, by Ray Dalio. Read: 99 Bottles of OOP, A Practical Guide to Object-Oriented Design Reading: Incognito: The Secret Lives of the Brain, by David Eagleman. Reading: Programming Elixir. Writing: Summary/Learnings from Mindset, by Carol Dweck. Writing: Blog article on decluttering/my 100 things. Biked: 123km. Coding:  Forever project: Daryllxd, a bunch of tools I use to help keep track of my life. Added tagging to expenses. Added presentation to help me keep track of expenses better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Habits: The 100 Things Challenge</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/good-habits-decluttering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 13:18:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/good-habits-decluttering/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
 I have 103 things. Having few, high quality things has made my life easier because I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think that much. The point of the challenge is not having a limit, but limiting consumption. Impulse buys are the worst. Whenever you want to buy something, don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;ll miss out if you don&amp;rsquo;t buy it. Just wait for a few days before actually buying the thing.  I first heard about the 100 Things Challenge when I was a college student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike to Work Checklist</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/bike-to-work-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 05:54:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/bike-to-work-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Bike to Work Checklist:  Work things.  Bag (rain cover). Computer (mouse, mousepad, keyboard, charger). Headphones (charging cables). Camera (batteries, cables, charger). Phone (charger). Wallet. Keys. Water bottle. Lunch (lunch box, utensils). Supplements.  Bike-specific things.  Front light. Back light. Bike lock. Hand pump. Multi-tool. 2x inner tube. Patch kit. Tire levers.  Clothing  Extra shirt. Jacket.  Deodorant. Sun screen. Facial routine (facial wash, toner, serum, moisturizer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Preparations 😱</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/hiking-preparations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 18:53:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/hiking-preparations/</guid>
      <description>1 week before: Pre-climb/itineraries. 🏔  Confirm itinerary.
 When to leave/meeting place, expected costs, options re: going to the jump-off point. Required permits for the climb. Confirm assignments: who&amp;rsquo;s the team leader, assistant leader/sweeper, medic. Get contact details/person to contact in case of emergency for all hikers. Get a contact person in Manila or wherever you are where you can send climb updates to. Required clothing/tools (cold wear, gloves, trekking poles).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Guide: Korea in Winter</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/travel-guide-korea-in-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 13:18:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/travel-guide-korea-in-winter/</guid>
      <description>Getting the Visa (Philippines): Visa requirements are on the Korean embassy page.
If your parents are retired (they don&amp;rsquo;t have an ITR), you can use your ITR as a substitute. My brother is in school so I used my ITR since I was sponsoring his trip.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think you need to be physically present when applying for the Visa. We forgot a requirement (my brother&amp;rsquo;s school certificate) the first time we got there so we re-applied a few days after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 15:38:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/start/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start blogging again. And this time I want to stick to this for good (like for the rest of my life). A few years back I did the Project 365 thing where you took a picture of the day for 365 days. I really liked that year since I actively tried to do something per day so surely writing about things should have that kind of effect 😱</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>