<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Learn. Create. Ship.</title>
    <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Learn. Create. Ship.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:48:14 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daryll.codes/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Recap, 20180209</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-2018-02-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:48:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/weekly-recap-2018-02-09/</guid>
      <description>Read: Principles, by Ray Dalio. Read: 99 Bottles of OOP, A Practical Guide to Object-Oriented Design Reading: Incognito: The Secret Lives of the Brain, by David Eagleman. Reading: Programming Elixir. Writing: Summary/Learnings from Mindset, by Carol Dweck. Writing: Blog article on decluttering/my 100 things. Biked: 123km. Coding:  Forever project: Daryllxd, a bunch of tools I use to help keep track of my life. Added tagging to expenses. Added presentation to help me keep track of expenses better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike to Work Checklist</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/bike-to-work-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 05:54:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/bike-to-work-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Bike to Work Checklist:  Work things.  Bag (rain cover). Computer (mouse, mousepad, keyboard, charger). Headphones (charging cables). Camera (batteries, cables, charger). Phone (charger). Wallet. Keys. Water bottle. Lunch (lunch box, utensils). Supplements.  Bike-specific things.  Front light. Back light. Bike lock. Hand pump. Multi-tool. 2x inner tube. Patch kit. Tire levers.  Clothing  Extra shirt. Jacket.  Deodorant. Sun screen. Facial routine (facial wash, toner, serum, moisturizer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking Preparations 😱</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/hiking-preparations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 18:53:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/hiking-preparations/</guid>
      <description>1 week before: Pre-climb/itineraries. 🏔  Confirm itinerary.
 When to leave/meeting place, expected costs, options re: going to the jump-off point. Required permits for the climb. Confirm assignments: who&amp;rsquo;s the team leader, assistant leader/sweeper, medic. Get contact details/person to contact in case of emergency for all hikers. Get a contact person in Manila or wherever you are where you can send climb updates to. Required clothing/tools (cold wear, gloves, trekking poles).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Guide: Korea in Winter</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/travel-guide-korea-in-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 13:18:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/travel-guide-korea-in-winter/</guid>
      <description>Getting the Visa (Philippines): Visa requirements are on the Korean embassy page.
If your parents are retired (they don&amp;rsquo;t have an ITR), you can use your ITR as a substitute. My brother is in school so I used my ITR since I was sponsoring his trip.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think you need to be physically present when applying for the Visa. We forgot a requirement (my brother&amp;rsquo;s school certificate) the first time we got there so we re-applied a few days after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start</title>
      <link>https://daryll.codes/posts/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 15:38:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daryll.codes/posts/start/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start blogging again. And this time I want to stick to this for good (like for the rest of my life). A few years back I did the Project 365 thing where you took a picture of the day for 365 days. I really liked that year since I actively tried to do something per day so surely writing about things should have that kind of effect 😱</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>